readypulse.com 2015-12-29

# Privacy Policy | ReadyPulse

**Last Changes to Privacy Policy: June 9, 2014**

We are strongly committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. The policies below are applicable to the ReadyPulse.com website, the Skorebase.com website, however accessed and/or used), whether via personal computers, mobile devices or otherwise, and other interactive features, applications or downloads that are operated by us that are available through these websites and post this Privacy Policy (collectively “Website”) produced and maintained by ReadyPulse, Inc. (collectively “Company” or “we”, “us”, or “our”). We have established this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to let you know the kinds of personal information we may gather during your visit to the Website, why we gather your information, what we use your personal information for, when we might disclose your personal information, and how you can manage your personal information.

Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered online at our Website. It does not apply to information that you may submit to us offline, or to websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link.

**By visiting our Website, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Website. We reserve the right to modify or amend the terms of our Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. Your continued use of our Website and our affiliate sites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. If we intend to apply the modifications or amendments to this Privacy Policy retroactively, we will provide you with notice of the modifications or amendments.**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or don’t see your concerns addressed here, you should contact us by email at privacy@readypulse.com.

**Controllers of Personal Information**

Any personal information provided to or to be gathered by Company is controlled primarily by ReadyPulse, Inc., located at 1600 A El Camino Real, San Carlos, CA 94070.

_**What Information About Me Is Collected and Stored?**_

Company adheres to the highest standards of ethical practices in all of our operations and is dedicated to protecting the privacy of all visitors to our Website.

We collect two basic types of information from you in conjunction with your use of the Website and any services offered thereon, personal information and non-personal information. Personal information is information that you may supply to us, as described more fully below, i.e., when you place an order, complete a survey, register as a subscriber, upload content or provide your e-mail address. Personal information is any information that can individually identify you and includes, among other things, your name, e-mail address, telephone number, postal address, credit card, billing and contact information. Non-personal information includes information that does not personally identify you, but it may include tracking and usage information about your location, demographics, use of the Website and the Internet.

**Personal Information**

There are a number of circumstances in which you may supply us with your personal information. The following lists the most common ways in which we may collect your personal information.

  * Registration for an account on the Website
  * Profile information that you provide for your user profile
  * Request for customer service or other assistance
  * Service related communications, e.g. account verification; technical notification
  * Submission of content or other data and information on any part of the Website that permits it
  * Any other place on the Website where you knowingly volunteer personal information

**Non-Personal Information**

In addition, when you interact with the Service, we may collect certain information that does not identify you individually and our servers may automatically keep an activity log of your use of our Service (“Non-Personal Information”). Generally, we collect and store the following categories of Non-Personal Information:

  * Non-identifiable demographic data such as age, and gender as part of collecting personal information
  * Device information about your computer, mobile device, or other device that you use to access the Website. This information may include IP address, geolocation information, unique device identifiers, browser type, browser language, and other transactional information.
  * Analytics and usage information about your use of the Website and any services offered thereon.
  * Additional “traffic data” and log files such as time of access, date of access, software crash reports, session identification number, access times, and referring website addresses.
  * Other information regarding your use of the Website and any services offered thereon.

**Registration Information**

So that we can provide you with the most efficient and enhanced experience if you subscribe to our services, you and each of your authorized users must register for a personal account accessible through a confidential password that you select. For purposes of registration and use of our services, we collect identifiable information about you and your authorized users such as your name, user ID and email address and may collect billing information. We also collect and store information that you enter into this Website or that you provide to any customer service representatives, in conjunction with requests for more information.

**Data Collection**

You may, but are not obligated to, upload Content (as defined in the Terms of Use) via the Website. This information may be shared with our subscribers and/or displayed publicly as described in further detail below.

We may also collect information about you that we receive from other sources. In addition to the information you upload or otherwise submit, without limitation ReadyPulse may collect the following:

  * Information from social media networks gathered using such network’s official APIs. The data gathered may include the following data points to the extent that are available for collection via the official APIs of the social networks, including without limitation social network id, name, bio, user picture, gender, location, audience information (followers/following), content (text and media) posted by the user on brand’s social pages, comments on the posts, social engagement information (such as Likes, comments, shares).
  * Information from social media ID logins (in connection with the Brand Ambassador program), including without limitation user name, social network id, gender, email, content posted including text and media.
  * Information from social media logins on social promotions applications (Pulse Promotions), including without limitation user name, social network id, email, gender, contest specific actions.
  * Information from 3rd party social network analysis providers.
  * Information from websites where the ReadyPulse Uploader Tool is displayed (subject to the separate ReadyPulse Services Privacy Policy located at (“ReadyPulse Services Privacy Policy).
  * Information from the Brand Ambassador Portal located at http://ambassadors.readypulse.com (subject to the separate ReadyPulse Services Privacy Policy.

Such information may be shared with subscribers and/or displayed publicly as described in further detail below. When you post, publish or otherwise submit content via social media networks and/or other Readypulse.com services, you provide some personal information, such as your name, a social network username, and your email address. Some of this information, for example, your name and username, is listed publicly on our Website, shared with our customers and subscribers and associated with content uploaded or otherwise submitted by you.

**Collection of Your Source IP Address/Location Information**

We will collect and store location information about you on the Website and associated with your account that you volunteer on the Website or enable through the Website or your device. We also collect and store your device’s source IP address which may disclose the location of your device at the time you access the Website.

**Collection of Personal and Non-Personal Information From Other Sources**

We also may collect and store information about you that we receive from other sources (including by us from our offline interactions with you).

**Anonymous Information**

In addition, when you interact with the Website, our servers may keep an activity log that does not identify you individually (“Anonymous Information”). Generally, this information is collected through “traffic data”. We collect and store certain administrative and traffic information with each use of the service or Website including: source IP address, time of access, date of access, web page(s), software crash reports, type of browser used, session identification number, search terms, search results, access times and referring websites addresses.

**Use of Cookies and Spyware**

We never use or install spyware on your computer, nor do we use spyware to retrieve information from your computer.  
Like many websites, we use “cookies”, which are small text files that are stored on your computer or equipment when you visit certain online pages that record your preferences. We use cookies to track use of our Website and online services. We may also use cookies to monitor traffic, improve the Website and make it easier and/or relevant for your use. You may occasionally get cookies from companies advertising on our behalf. We do not control these cookies, and these cookies are not subject to this privacy policy.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but, if you prefer, you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. For more information on cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information provided by the Interactive Advertising Bureau at www.allaboutcookies.org.

Like some Websites, we may use web beacons. A web beacon (also known as “action tags” or “single-pixel gifs”) is an invisible graphic on a web page that is programmed to collect non-personally identifiable information about your use of a given website. Like cookies, web beacons allow Company and its technology providers to summarize overall usage patterns for our analysis and provide personalized services and advertising content. We do not share or provide personally identifiable information we may collect through such web beacons, such as names, e-mail addresses and phone numbers with our advertisers without your express permission.

**Is Information Collected From Children?**

The Company provide services that are intended for a general audience. Users are required to provide their dates of birth to access certain features of our website. If a user identifies himself or herself as under 13, we comply with COPPA, which, among other things, requires verifiable parental consent if we collect personal information from such a user. In the process of obtaining parental consent, we provide parents with a description of the information we collect from our users, how that information is used, who that information is shared with, what types of information may be made public, and how a parent may access their child’s personal information or request that their child’s account be disabled. We will not knowingly ask children under the age of 13 to provide any personal information.

**How We Use Your Information?**

We may use your Personal and Non-Personal Information in the following ways:

**General Uses**

We also use the information we learn from you to help us personalize and continually improve your experience on the Website. We use the information to:

  * Provide you with the content, products and services requested, including without limitation the advertising services described in the Terms of Use (defined below);
  * Upload your content to our Service as you request;
  * Communicate with you about your account or transactions with us and send you information about features and enhancements on our Website;
  * Communicate with you about changes to our policies;
  * Communicate with you about displaying your content externally;
  * Personalize content and experiences on our Website, including providing you reports, recommendations and feedback based on your preferences;
  * Optimize or improve our products, services and operations;
  * Automatically update the Service on your device;
  * Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal;
  * Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Service.

We also use this information to improve our services and websites, prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our websites and, as described below, enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf.

**Who Do We Provide Your Information To?**

**Data Publishing**

Most of the information you provide us, including without limitation any Content uploaded or otherwise submitted by you and excluding Registration Information, is information you are giving us consent to share with third parties, including our paid subscribers, and otherwise make public. The information that you upload or otherwise submit via the Website may be used and/or published as set forth in the ReadyPulse Terms of Use located at http://www.readypulse.com/tos or other applicable Terms of Use (e.g., the Skorebase.com Terms of Use) (collectively, “Terms of Use”), including use for advertising and promotional purposes, and will be a permanent part of this Website and any derivative works incorporating such information.

When you share information or content like photos, videos, and links, via the Website or otherwise, you should think carefully about what you are making public. Such information may be associated with other information we collect, including without limitation Personal Information and information about you collected via social media, and made public and/or shared with our customers, including paid subscribers to our services.

**Service and Feedback**

We may also use your Personal Information to provide services, provide customer service, track your compliance with the Website’s rules and regulations, or for editorial and feedback purposes (to the extent that is explained when you provide the information).

**Use of Anonymous Information**

We use Anonymous Information to help us determine how people use parts of the Website and who our users are so we can improve our Website and ensure that it is as appealing as we can make it for as many people as possible. We also use Anonymous Information to provide statistical “ratings” information in aggregated form to our partners and other third parties about how our users collectively use the Website. We may also use or share Anonymous Information (or other information, other than Personal Information) in any other manner that we deem appropriate or necessary.

**Third-Party Agents**

We occasionally have third party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and partners that perform functions on our behalf, such as marketing, analytics, credit card processing, providing customer service, fraud protection, etc. These entities have access to the Personal Information needed to perform their functions and are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of that Personal Information. They are restricted from using, selling, distributing or altering this data in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Website.

**Business Transfers**

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy websites, subsidiaries, or business units. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy (unless, of course, the customer consents otherwise). Also, in the unlikely event that ReadyPulse, Inc., or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will of course be one of the transferred assets.

**Transactional partners**

We may share non-personal information with our partners and others from time to time. Examples of such non-personal information include the number of users who visited this Website during a specific time period. This information generally is shared in an aggregated form.

**Emergency Situations**

We may also use or disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or the Website; (b) protect and defend our rights or property, the Website or our users, and (c) act under emergency circumstances to protect the personal safety of us, our affiliates, customers, subscribers, agents, or other users of the Website or the public.

**Use of Non-Personal Information**

We may disclose or share Non-Personal Information (or other information, other than Personal Information) in any other manner that we deem appropriate or necessary. Among other things, we will disclose Non-Personal Information to third parties to help us determine how people use parts of the Website and services offered thereon and who our users are so we can improve the Website and our services. We will also disclose Non-Personal Information to our partners and other third parties about how our users collectively use the Website and services.

**Company E-mail and Text Communications**

E-mail communications sent from us or through us are designed to make your experience more efficient. By using the Website, including without limitation participating in any services offered thereon, you specifically agree to accept and consent to receiving e-mail communications initiated from us or through us, which include, without limitation: message notification e-mails, e-mails informing you about promotions we run and emails informing you of new and existing features we provide. If you change your mobile phone service provider, the notification service may be deactivated for your phone number and you may need to re-enroll in the notification service. Company reserves the right to cancel the notification service at any time. If you do not wish to receive any of our e-mail communications, you may unsubscribe by selecting to turn off automatic alerts.

**What Steps Are Taken To Keep Personal Information Secure?**

The importance of security for all Personal Information associated with you is of utmost concern to us. We exercise great care in providing secure transmission of your information from your PC to our servers. Personal Information collected by our Website is stored in secure operating environments that are not available to the public. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you.

While we try our best to safeguard your Personal Information once we receive it, no transmission of data over the Internet or any other public network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

**Your Obligations to Keep Your Access Rights Secure**

You promise to: (a) provide true, accurate, current and complete information about yourself and your business as prompted by the Website’s registration form (such information being the “Registration Data”) and (b) maintain and promptly update the Registration Data to keep it true, accurate, current and complete. If you provide any information that is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete, or Company has reasonable grounds to suspect that such information is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete, Company has the right to suspend or terminate your account and refuse any and all current or future use of the Website (or any portion thereof). You are entirely responsible for the security and confidentiality of your password and account and any other log-in information. Furthermore, you are entirely responsible for any and all activities that occur under your account or user ID. You agree to immediately notify us of any unauthorized use of your account, user ID or any other breach of security of which you become aware. You are responsible for taking precautions and providing security measures best suited for your situation and intended use of the services and Website. Please note that anyone able to provide your personally identifiable information will be able access your account so you should take reasonable steps to protect this information.

**How Do We Use Your Information In Promotions?**

If you participate a contest or other promotion, your Information may be disclosed as required by law, by us or by a third party using our Services, for example, on a winners’ list or we may require you to consent to the use of your Information in advertising materials. In addition, our Company may suggest other promotions that are sponsored or co-sponsored by a third party. If disclosed to you on the promotion registration page and/or Rules, those third parties may obtain the Information you submit for that promotion. We have no control over such a third party’s use of your Information, and any such third party is not subject to this Privacy Policy.

**How Can We Transfer Your Personal Information?**

Your information collected through the Website, or otherwise, may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Company, its Affiliates, customers, subscribers or service providers maintain facilities. Company, its Affiliates, customers, subscribers or service providers may transfer information that we collect about you, including personal information across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. If you are located in the United States or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from US law, please note that we may transfer information, including personal information, to a country and jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction. By registering for and/or using the Website, including any services offered thereon, you consent to the transfer of information to the US or to any other country in which Company, its Affiliates, customers, subscribers or service providers maintain facilities and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy.

**How Long Do We Keep Your Information?**

Following termination or deactivation of your account, Company, its Affiliates, its customers, its subscribers or its service providers may retain information (including your profile information) and user Content for a commercially reasonable time for backup, archival, and/or audit purposes. If you have any questions about termination or deactivation of your account, please contact us directly at privacy@readypulse.com. **Following termination or deactivation, you are responsible for removing any ReadyPulse widgets or other uploader tools installed on your website. Failure to remove such ReadyPulse widgets or other uploader tools may result in our continued collection of information from you, your customers and your website.**

**What Happens When I Link To or From Another Web Site?**

This Website may contain links to other websites operated by affiliates of Company or third parties. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy for Company do not apply to information gathered through these other websites. These other sites may also send their own cookies to you, collect your data or solicit your Personal Information. Always be aware of where you end up. We are not responsible for the actions and privacy policies of third parties and other websites. We encourage you to be aware of when you leave this Website and read the privacy policies of each and every website that you visit.

**Governing Law/Assignment**

The Website is published in the United States. We make every effort to protect the personal identifiable information of all users of the Website. We attempt to comply with local data protection and consumer rights laws to the extent they may apply to the Company services. If you are uncertain whether this privacy policy conflicts with the applicable local privacy laws where you are located, you should not submit your content and/or Personal Information to Company.

We make no representation that our website is governed by or operated in accordance with laws of other nations. By using our website, you acknowledge that U.S. law provides a lower standard of protection for personal data than the laws of other countries including, but not limited to, the European Union. Consequently, you waiver any claims that may arise under the laws and regulations that apply to you in or of any other country or jurisdiction.

We may change ownership or corporate organization while providing the Website and services. As a result, please be aware that we may transfer your information to another Company that is affiliated with us or with which we have merged. Under such circumstances Company would to the extent possible require the acquiring party to follow the practices described in this Privacy Policy, as it may be amended from time to time.

**Changes to This Policy**

As our Services continue to develop, we may add new services and features. In the event that these additions affect our Privacy Policy, this document will be updated appropriately and we will send explicit notice to all our users to notify them that a change to our policy has been made. We will post those changes prominently so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone. We do, however, recommend that you read this Privacy Policy each time you use our website in case you missed our notice of changes to the Privacy Policy. We will never, however, materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of customer information we have previously collected without your express consent.

**How Do I Opt-Out or Correct Information About Me**

You may always opt-out of receiving future e-mail messages and newsletters from Company. We provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about you. We also give you access to a broad range of information about your account to permit you to correct or update Personal Information that you have previously provided to us. To do so, you can send us a message at privacy@readypulse.com.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

If you are a resident of the State of California, we provide you with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options such as your right to opt-out (which we may sometimes refer to as “unsubscribe”) or opt-in for disclosure of your Personal Information to third parties for marketing purposes. Therefore, pursuant to the California Civil Code, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of the third parties that received your Personal Information for marketing purposes during the preceding year.

If you are a California resident and wish to request information about how to exercise your third-party disclosure choices, please contact our Privacy Administrator at privacy@readypulse.com or:

**ReadyPulse, Inc.**  
**Attn: California Privacy Rights**  
**1600 A El Camino Real, San Carlos, CA 94070.**

All requests must be labelled “Privacy Rights” on the e-mail subject line or envelope or post card. For all requests, please clearly state that the request is related to “My California Privacy Rights” and include your name, street address, city, state, zip code and e-mail address. We are not responsible for notices that are not labelled or sent properly, or do not have complete information.
